KYLE W. SINGLETON

Los Angeles, CA (540) 798-8372 kwsingleton.com kyle.singleton@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Biomedical Engineering PhD with focus in medical informatics and disease modeling. Experience working with engineering, statistics, and clinical personnel to implement and deploy software in clinical trials research. Proficient at data cleaning and statistical modelling with R. Previous experience with additional statistics packages such as MATLAB and SPSS.

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

Doctor of Philosophy, Biomedical Engineering

July 2016

Dissertation: Investigating Predictive Disease Model Transportability through Cohort Simulation and Causal Analysis Advisors: Alex A.T. Bui and William Hsu

University of Virginia Charlottesville, VA

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

May 2006

Minor: Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Researcher

2012 - 2016

UCLA Medical Imaging Informatics, Los Angeles, CA

- Supervised graduate student team, reviewing and cleaning 500+ brain cancer cases for predictive modelling.
- Evaluated a novel simulation technique for interpreting the external validity of models between patient cohorts.
- Processed cancer data from public repositories (National Lung Screening Trial, The Cancer Genome Atlas).

National Library of Medicine Fellow

2008 - 2012

UCLA NLM Medical Imaging Informatics Training Program, Los Angeles, CA

- Programmed and supported a tablet based system used to survey 20,000+ patients in three Los Angeles clinics.
- Completed coursework in medical informatics, statistics, and machine learning.

Post-baccalaureate Fellow 2006 - 2008

National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD

Section on Stroke Diagnostics and Therapeutics, NINDS

- Designed new imaging workflow, accelerating image availability for stroke research tasks.
- Developed a 100 patient case MRI stroke atlas.

Undergraduate Researcher

2005 - 2006

Computational Systems Biology Lab, Charlottesville VA

• Collaborated with two students to create metabolic network reconstruction of Leishmania major.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: R, Java, C#, ASP.NET, MATLAB, C++ Informatics Tools: R, SPSS, MATLAB, RapidMiner, Weka, GENIE

Medical Data Standards: DICOM, XML, HIPAA

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (2 OF 6)

Singleton KW, Speier W, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Motivating the additional use of external validity: examining transportability in a model of glioblastoma multiforme. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2014;2014:1930–9.

Singleton KW, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Transfer and transport: incorporating causal methods for improving predictive models. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2014;:amiajnl–2014–002968. doi:10.1136/amiajnl-2014-002968